am335xx gpio set
128 pins  = 32 pins * 4 banks
each register bank size is 4k and having uniq addr. range.
configuration and operation registers
output enable(OE)
DATAIN, DATAOUT, CLEARDATAOUT, SETDATAOUT

1. define pin config into new gpio node with name led
2. register device with platform core 
3. define probe function 
    use gpiolib api to access pin configuration
4. define write function to perform output operation on led pin

