

git clone" of buildroot, and did nothing more than:
> 
>   $ make beaglebone_defconfig
>   $ make

>   * kernel 4.0.x
>   * glibc 2.21
>   * binutils 2.25
>   * gcc 4.9.x


buildroot generates only boot images(kernel, boitliader, rootfs)
yocto generate bootimages + appilcation rpm pacakages

openembded: collection of recepies
alternative to buildroot yocto is on top of it
uses python scripts
for each image py script is there we called it as recepies

app layer recepies
 bsp(for soc) layer recepies(all boot images comes under this)


application can updates as rpm packages
so no need to compile all build images again


poky: samople scripts
how to combine openembedded and bsp recepies to generate image
reuse and customize the poky scripts to generate full scale linux destribution


 birbake : build tool
buildtool which reads the recepies and do ooeration specified


