Interview question: How do you test whether there are memory leaks in a Linux application
  valgind --leak-check=yes

Can i lock a spinlock in one CPU and unlock it another CPU?
No. When spinlock is taken we disable interrupts, preemption on local CPU. These things need to be restored in unlock. So all should happen in same thread context.

what is the maximum amount of time CPU can be in critical section after acquiring spinlock?
Soft lock up time is dependent on kernel.watchdog_thresh parameter. Timer is 2*watchdog_thresh 
;Example [root@sys ~]# cat /proc/sys/kernel/watchdog_thresh 10 So soft lock up will be after 20 seconds. This parameter is configurable.

Ensure that watchdog is enabled also by checking the watchdog kernel parameter - sysctl -ar ^kernel.watchdog$

Difference between GFP_KERNEL and GFP_ATOMIC??
GFP_KERNEL: used in process context
 GFP_ATOMIC: used in interrupt context
If memory allocation is happening in process context where process is allowed to sleep, using GFP_KERNEL make sense because the call to kmalloc() with GFP_KERNEL flag can put the process to sleep (block) in order to free up the memory if sufficient memory not available. Using GFP_ATOMIC instructs the memory allocator never to sleep(block) and therefore it should be used in situations where it cannot sleep i.e it must remain atomic such as interrupt handlers, bottom halves and process context that is already holding a lock.. kmalloc with GFP_ATOMIC is will return error if sufficient free memory not available rather than block the process as in case of kmalloc with GFP_KERNEL

what happens internally during context switch in Linux kernel?
loading and unloading of PCB...

Which file in Linux gives you information about memory zones 
/proc/zoneinfo

What is buffer/cache?

The buffer-cache is main memory (i.e. RAM) used as a cache to reduce the number of physical read/writes  from mass-storage devices (like hard disks, for example),

what is the asm-generic folder in Linux source code. What it contains?
Optimized lowest level operations (register/assembly level) which work on all supported CPU architectures like e.g. optimized XOR with different parameter and register numbers, page table fixups, bit operations, atomic operations, kernel bug handling, cache flushing, locks, checksum calculation, etc. Those can also call arch-specific implementations.

Difference between IO Mapped IO and Memory Mapped IO??
The main difference between memory mapped IO and IO mapped IO is that the memory mapped IO uses the same address space for both memory and IO device while the IO mapped IO uses two separate address spaces for memory and IO device.

Difference between kmalloc and vmalloc??
The difference is in usage and the performance. vmalloc gives you virtually contiguous memory rather than physically contiguous memory given by kmalloc. Not all applications needs physically contiguous memory such as DMA transactions. If there is no requirement of physically contiguous memory than vmalloc can be used. For example, insmod uses vmalloc to allocate memory for loading the kernel module into the kernel memory As far as performance is concerned, vmalloc affects the performance because vmalloc have to create and maintain the page table entries. Since the memory is virtually contiguous, several virtual-to-physical address mappings have to added to the page table. This also adds more pressure on the TLB, where the cache entries stores recent virtual to physical address mappings when accessing this allocated memory. In worst case scenario, this can lead to thrashing, causing severe paging and page faults, eventually bringing down the performance of the systems.

How can i find out the Count of number of times a process has been preempted in Linux?
  getrusage should be able to help

what does malloc(0) return?
After successfull allocation in malloc(), a pointer to the block of memory is returned otherwise NULL value is returned which indicates the failure of allocation.

what is NUMA?
Non uniform memory access. It is a way of grouping processors so that memory can be shared among them. It takes different time for each processor to access the memory in this method

will a module be loaded if it has while(1) loop in module_init function. ?
it may hang the system , insmod never end , difficult to kill this process

what is the maximum memory that can be allocated using vmalloc?
it's depends on the available physical memory but always be at least 128M‌B on the x86 

What is the maximum memory that can be allocated using kmalloc?
kmalloc allocates in continuous pages of physical memory and return the virtual pointer. kmalloc maximum size in one allocation is depends on slab allocators, currently we are using SLUB allocator.(2008 onwards) So calculation of maximum size in one allocation of kmalloc is For SLAB allocator - MAX_ORDER + PAGE_SHIFT - 1 < =25 ? MAX_ORDER + PAGE_SHIFT -1 : 25 // slab.h 2^25 = ~32 MB For SLUB & SLOB allocator MAX_ORDER +PAGE_SHIFT-1 2^22 = ~4MB ( If max_order is default to 11) Default max_order is 11 and page_shift is 12 We can change max_order in kernel config. max_order is used for buddy allocation, page_shift is offset.

What is the difference between VIRT, RES and SHR fields in top command?
“VIRT” is the total amount of memory consumed by each process “RES” is the memory consumed by process in RAM “SHR” is the amount of memory shared with other processes


what is the system call used by malloc and free??
It uses *brk()* system call to allocate chunk of memory and size of heap is adjusted using *sbrk()* call. If requested memory is larger than MMAP_THRESOLD bytes then glibc malloc() will allocates memory as private anonymous mapping using *mmap()* system call. Default value of MMAP_THRESOLD is 128 bytes. Memory allocated using mmap() can only be freed to system using munmap().

What is the maximum memory that I can allocate using malloc??
Linux memory management is one of the most/best tricky topic. In Linux Everything is Work with Virtual Memory. Virtual memory Limits - For 32 bit system = 2^32 address For 64 bit system = 2^48 address (still we are not using whole 64 bit because 256TB is sufficient memory for 64 bit machine). This Virtual Memory address ranges are divided as User space virtual memory and kernel space virtual memory. For 32 bit We have options in kernel config like 2G/2G , 1G/3G, and 3G/1G. (User/Kernel). For 64 bit divided into lower section (user) and upper section (kernel), vm depends on page tables levels but generally it's 4 level page tables in which 128 TB for user space and 128 TB for Kernel space. Malloc()- It return virtual memory, but vm needs to be mapped with available physical memory, For 64 bit theoretically maximun it will allocate ram+swap size memory. For 32 bit theoretically maximum you can allocate depends on user space virtual memory , vmsplit configuration (2G/2G) 2G max you can allocate. Note=overcommit is giving virtual memory with no guarantee that it will mapped with physical memory or not. If fails to map ur app will crash. malloc always allocate more than u requested Unless u use ur memory malloc won't allocate.
