process memory allocation
1. allocation in user space - virtual addr.
2. allocation in kernel space - linear addr

on 32 bit system process allocates max 3gb space

vma having detail of memory maping
task_struct -> mmap -> vma 
memory has been mapped into diffrent blocks called as segments(Heap, stack, data, text seg.). each seg. having vma struct which consist of mapping info.
each segments is a group of 1 or more pages.

process blocks/seg. divided into two tyeps of mapping:
1. file backed--code, data, .so
2. anonymous pages -- heao, stack, bss

user space to kernel space process addr. transalation:

segments addr.(virtual) are translated into page addr.(linear) then kernel translates page addr to phy. frame addr. to process data.
On 32 bit system page size 4k.

page table mngmnt:
page table lvl indirection policys
2 lvl, 3 lvl for 32 bit sys
4, 5 lvl for 64 bit sys


struct vm_area_struct is created at each mmap call issued from user space 
cat /proc/pid/maps repre. vm_area_struct fields related to that process.

struct task_struct --> struct mm_struct --> struct vm_area_struct





